http://www.healthyhearing.com/privacy-policy

Hearing aid apps: What you need to know
Most hearing aid manufacturers offer accompanying smartphone apps that let users control their hearing aid settings, monitor their batteries, and many other features.
Read more
Tinnitus coping strategies for negative thoughts and rumination
Here's how to break the chain of rumination that can occur when you have chronic tinnitus, or ringing in the ears. Once you understand why it's happening, you can start to fight back. Read more
Websites and blogs about hearing loss and tinnitus
Looking for websites, support groups or forums to connect with other people who have hearing loss or hearing impairment? Here are some of the top websites we follow for insights into hearing loss and tinnitus, as well as patient perspectives.
Read more
How cold weather and moisture can impact hearing aids
Learn how to prevent hearing aid damage due to cold, wet winter weather, and how to troubleshoot problems if they arise. Plus, how to protect your ears and why tinnitus is more common when it's cold. Read more
Menu
Find a clinic
Hearing loss
Hearing loss overview
Symptoms
Causes
Tests
Hearing aids
For using our Site
This privacy policy applies to the Healthy Hearing website (the “Site”). The Site contains links to other sites. Once you enter another website (whether through an advertisement, service or content link), be aware that Healthy Hearing is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy statements of each and every website you visit through a link or advertisement on Healthy Hearing as well as any of the clinics listed in our directory. Healthy Hearing works with partners (“Corporate Partners”) that include hearing aid manufacturers, independently owned hearing aid dispensing clinics, networks of hearing aid dispensing clinics and their parent companies, as well as non-profit organizations. Note that some of the information we collect from you may be shared with our Corporate Partners, see below. Please see the privacy policies of these partners for how they might use your information.
Non-personal information we collect
Healthy Hearing collects non-personal information about your use of the Site, special promotions and newsletters.
Cookies
Healthy Hearing collects non-personal information about your use of the Site and your use of the websites of Corporate Partners through the use of cookies. Every computer is assigned a different cookie by the Site. The information collected by cookies (1) helps us dynamically generate advertising and content on web pages or in newsletters, (2) allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our website and selected Corporate Partners' sites, (3) how many people open our emails and (4) for what purposes these actions are being taken. Healthy Hearing may use cookie information to target certain advertisements to your browser or to determine the popularity of certain content or advertisements. Cookies also are used to facilitate a user's log-in, as navigation aids and as session timers.
Your browser software can be set to reject all cookies. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject our cookies, certain functions and conveniences of our website may not work properly but you do not have to accept our cookies in order to productively use our site. Healthy Hearing does not link non-personal information from cookies to personally identifiable information without your permission.
Identifiable information we collect
Healthy Hearing collects personally identifiable information you provide when you sign up to receive our email newsletter, call the Healthy Hearing contact phone number, send us an email, send us a message through our online forms or through public forums, reach out to Healthy Hearing via online chat, call one of the clinic phone numbers posted on the Site, talk to agents within the Healthy Hearing call center, post a review and rating of a clinic in our directory or take our online hearing test. We use the personally identifiable information you provide to respond to your questions, provide you specific services you select, help you find a clinic in your area, help you navigate the information on the Site, conduct follow-up surveys and send you emails about website maintenance and updates.
Newsletters and emails
Please note: Healthy Hearing does not send out paper newsletters in the mail.
At various times as you use the Site, you will be given the opportunity to sign up for recurring informational email newsletters from Healthy Hearing. At the time you sign up for our email newsletters or at any time thereafter, you can choose to opt out of receiving additional email newsletters from Healthy Hearing.
In order to subscribe to our email newsletter, we need contact information such as your name and email address. This personally identifiable information may be shared with our Corporate Partners when you subscribe to our newsletter. You can unsubscribe from the newsletters by simply clicking on the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email newsletter. You will then receive an email from our automated unsubscribe service. Click the "unsubscribe" button in the email. You will be unsubscribed from the newsletter within two to three business days. If you are experiencing difficulties with our automated unsubscribe service, you can email Healthy Hearing at enewsletter@healthyhearing.com. Our staff will unsubscribe you in two to three business days.
In some cases, when you click on a link or an advertisement in an email or newsletter, your browser may be momentarily directed to the website of a third party which, acting on behalf of Healthy Hearing (see Disclosure to website service and content contractors, below), notes or "counts" your response to the email or newsletter before redirecting your browser to its proper destination; this redirection process will not be apparent to you.
Call tracking and consumer surveys
When you call a clinic from the phone number posted on our Site the call may be routed through a Healthy Hearing call center to assist in connecting with the clinic. These calls may be recorded for quality assurance. Call data and recordings are made available to our Corporate Partners in order to provide feedback about the call experience and outcome. For example, when a person calls “Clinic A” to make an appointment, the Healthy Hearing call center may answer the phone on behalf of the clinic and obtain some personally identifiable information before connecting the caller with the clinic. Healthy Hearing will also be noting the type and outcome of the call. Healthy Hearing may provide “Clinic A" with access to the recording of that phone call. Healthy Hearing does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices of these clinics. If you choose to call a clinic on the Site, review the privacy policy posted by this other organization to understand how that third party organization collects and uses your personally identifiable information. If you do not want to have your personally identifiable information shared in this way, do not call clinics using the numbers listed on Healthy Hearing and discontinue use of the Site.
Calls are also reviewed in order to identify a pool of potential candidates for follow-up surveys. These consumers are contacted by a Healthy Hearing call center for a brief survey about the outcome and the experience with the clinic they visited. The phone survey may be declined by the consumer. The survey data are reported to Corporate Partners. Call data and survey results may be provided to the public in aggregate form only.
Calling the Site or using online chat
When you contact the Site through any posted phone numbers or through online chat, your session may be recorded for quality assurance. During the call or chat session, Healthy Hearing may request personally identifiable information to assist you in navigating the Site or finding a clinic in your area. Call and chat data and recordings may be made available to our Corporate Partners in order to provide feedback about the call experience and outcome. If you do not want to have your personally identifiable information shared in this way, do not contact the Site through phone or online chat and discontinue use of the Site.
Downloading a free guide
In order to download a free guide from the Site, you must provide contact information such as your name and email address. This personally identifiable information may be shared with our Corporate Partners.
Public forums
As a service to our users, the Site features public forums where users with similar interests or medical conditions can share information and support one another. Clinic reviews are one such forum. We also offer online discussions moderated by medical or healthcare experts.
Any information (including personally identifiable information) you share in an online review or discussion is by design open to the public and is not a private, secure service. Think carefully before disclosing any personally identifiable or personal health information in any public forum. What you have written may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes.
Contact forms
This privacy policy does not protect you or your personally identifiable information when you send content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions to Healthy Hearing by email. If you want to keep your personally identifiable information, content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an email to Healthy Hearing. We try to answer every email within 48 business hours but we are not always able to do so.
Market research
Through email invitations, online surveys or online focus groups, the Healthy Hearing market research department or its operations contractors acting on its behalf, conducts research surveys in order to gather feedback about the Site, Corporate Partners and opinions on important healthcare issues.
When participating in a survey, we may ask you to submit personally identifiable information. This personally identifiable information may be reported to Corporate Partners. Cookies may be used to authenticate respondents or to help you pick up where you left off in a survey. If you have cookies disabled, you may not be able to participate in some studies. Cookies may be used to connect survey data with the Site’s usage characteristics. You will be notified when we would like to use cookies in this way and your consent will be requested for these cookies.
Information collected by third parties not acting on Healthy Hearing's behalf
Corporate Partners or advertisers on the Site may use their own cookies in advertisements served on the Site and in emails, special promotions or newsletters we send you. Some advertisers use companies other than Healthy Hearing to serve their ads and to monitor users' responses to ads, and these companies ("Ad Servers") may also collect non-personal information through the use of cookies on our website. In certain situations, information collection may be facilitated by momentarily directing your browser to the website of an Ad Server or other third party acting on behalf of the corporate partner, or advertiser before redirecting your browser to its proper destination (e.g., back to the Site to show the ad or to the advertiser's website); this redirection process will not be apparent to you.
We do not control these third parties' use of cookies or how they manage the non-personal information they gather through them. However, we do require corporate partners, advertisers and Ad Servers who collect cookie information through our website to agree that they will not collect any personally identifiable information from our website without your consent. They have promised us they will not link any non-personal information collected by them through cookies in advertising banners on our website to personally identifiable information they or others collect. Certain Ad Servers allow you to prevent them from collecting data through the use of cookies. In order to do so, you must opt-out of such data collection with each individual site. Currently, you can opt-out of cookies for several Ad Servers by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative gateway opt-out site. This website will also allow you to review the Ad Server's privacy policies.
Disclosure of your information
Except as set forth in this privacy policy or as specifically agreed to by you, Healthy Hearing will not disclose any personally identifiable information it gathers from you on our Site. We will only release personally identifiable information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your personally identifiable information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. In addition, we may disclose personal information as described below.
Disclosure of aggregate information
Healthy Hearing may provide aggregate information to third parties. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of the Site and the activities they conduct while on the Site. We might also inform a company (that may or may not be an advertiser on our site) that "30% of our users live east of the Mississippi" or that "25% of our users dispense hearing aids." Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this aggregate information. We require parties with whom we share aggregate information to agree they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable, such as by combining it with other databases.
How Healthy Hearing handles privacy and security internally
Listed below are some of the security procedures Healthy Hearing uses to protect your privacy:
Uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers
Closely monitors and limits the number of Healthy Hearing employees who have potential access to your personally identifiable information
Follows best practice for password security
Requires all Healthy Hearing employees to abide by this privacy policy and be subject to disciplinary action if they violate it
Backs up our systems daily to protect the integrity of your personally identifiable information
Despite Healthy Hearing's efforts to protect your personally identifiable information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted.
Contacting Healthy Hearing
Removing your personal information
If you have a complaint or problem, please email us at contacthh@healthyhearing.com. Our customer service department will forward your complaint to the appropriate internal Healthy Hearing department for a response or resolution. We try to answer every email within 48 business hours, but we may not always able to do so. If you want to (1) delete your personally identifiable information from our systems, or (2) update the personally identifiable information that you have provided to us, please email us at contacthh@healthyhearing.com.
If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy related problem, you may write to Healthy Hearing Privacy Help Desk at:
Healthy Hearing
PO Box 515381 #42919
Los Angeles, CA 90051-6681
Limitations on removing or changing information
Upon your request, we will delete your personally identifiable information from our active databases and where feasible from our back-up media. Be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to the Site from our servers.
Privacy policy acceptance
Your use of the Site will indicate acceptance of this privacy policy. You may, of course, choose to discontinue using the Site. Please exit the Site immediately if you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy.
